Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/mat-giladi (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Problem Solving Microsoft Excel Communication

Languages

Hebrew (Limited Working)
Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

Certified Personal Trainer (NASM-CPT)

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification

Alteryx Designer Advanced Certified

Honors-Awards

Rutgers Trustee Scholar
MVP of the Quarter
Top 3 Speaker
2nd Degree Black Belt - TKD
Bi-Annual Case Competition - 3rd
Place

Mathew Giladi

Incoming Business Analyst - McKinsey & Company | Incoming MBA Candidate - Deferred Admission Stanford GSB Fort Lee

Summary

My skill set is in data-driven problem solving and interpersonal communications.

As an online course creator, I collected qualitative data about customer needs through over 200 interviews and synthesized those findings into a strategic decision about the course's content – the decision was validated by the successful pre-sell. Now at Johnson & Johnson, I've been practicing quantitative analysis through my onthe-job learning of SQL, Alteryx, and Tableau, as well as Rutgers University's research methods course where I used SPSS to analyze data sets and develop insights.

Communication has been integral to my career. The success of many projects, such as the group training initiative at my 24 Hour Fitness location, depended on teamwork. I've also enjoyed client interaction as a personal trainer for 24 Hour Fitness, where I sold \$15,500 in one month and regularly managed about 20 clients. Earlier, as a presenter for Elevate Education, I got to present extensively, speaking to 3,000 students in 150 schools and ranked the #1 company speaker in the state.

Experience

McKinsey & Company Incoming Business Analyst November 2019 - Present (10 months)

Greater Boston Area

Johnson & Johnson 1 year 2 months

Portfolio and Capability Management Co-Op January 2020 - Present (8 months)

Skillman, NJ

Shortened Co-Op onboarding by 75%; working with multiple teams to develop a department-wide standard

Leading a root cause analysis with stakeholders to choose a vendor for a multi-customer data load process

Creating the team strategy and analyzing unexpected data patterns to secure \$1mm+ in J&J capital funding

Collaborating to automate truck loading and increase utilization by 32%; \$1mm + in potential cost savings

Managing a global team to standardize Divestiture's project planning and enable cross-region collaboration

Strategy and Emerging Capabilities Co-Op July 2019 - January 2020 (7 months) Bridgewater

Organized a cross-department Tableau training attended by 80% of local Co-Ops – \$10,000 cost avoidance

Led logistics for a world-wide innovation event, attended by 86% of the department across 6 countries

Collaborated with the Communications team to develop a framework for department's branding efforts

Developed a new video production process with 33% expected cost savings for the communications team

24 Hour Fitness
Personal Trainer
June 2018 - June 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Englewood Cliffs, NJ

Ranked top 1% (#15/2500+) of trainers throughout all 430+ gyms and #1 at my location

Generated and managed 23 clients in my 2nd month, selling \$15,500 with a 42.6% closing rate

Worked with clients to analyze their problems and create solutions to help them achieve their goals

Initiated, marketed, and led the gym's first group training program with the manager; generated 4 clients

Launched a low-cost educational program and created standard operating procedures for new trainers

Productivity Despite Distractions
Course Creator
December 2017 - June 2018 (7 months)
New Brunswick, NJ

Recruited and managed a team of three to develop an online productivity course based on 30+ books

Identified customer needs with my team by conducting 200+ interviews with potential customers

Validated product-market fit through a successful pre-sell with a 65% conversion rate

Implemented an innovative, low-cost yet high-quality video production studio to achieve 69% cost savings

Elevate Education
Presenter
May 2017 - March 2018 (11 months)
Hoboken, NJ

Earned a 99.44% average performance based on student feedback and ranked #1 speaker in the state

Delivered 150+ seminars about study skills to 3,000+ students in the Tri-State Area

Rutgers University–New Brunswick
Public Speaking Workshop Leader
February 2017 - February 2018 (1 year 1 month)
New Brunswick, NJ

Created, marketed, and taught a seven-week sponsored public speaking workshop for two semesters

Increased initial group size from one semester to the next by 38.5% (from 26 to 36 students)

Education

Stanford University Graduate School of Business Incoming MBA Candidate - Deferred Admission · (2020)

Rutgers University-New Brunswick
Bachelor of Science - BS, Health/Health Care Administration/
Management · (2016 - 2020)

Fort Lee High School High School Diploma, International Baccalaureate · (2012 - 2016)